Guide to the Pittsburgh Playhouse School of the Theater Records, 1934-1994 CTC.1981.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Pressbooks, Clippings, Brochures and Press Releases, 1934-1994; V.
  - Scrapbooks, 1933-1953; 2.
    - Pittsburgh Summer Playhouse scrapbook, 1933-1934 (Box 121B, Volume 4)
      Clippings, ephemera and programs related to the Pittsburgh Summer Playhouse of the Pittsburgh Little Theater and the Pittsburgh Civic Playhouse, 1933-34.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1940-1994; 3.
    This subseries contains a small amount of loose photocopied newspaper clippings, in chronological order. The majority of this material dates from after 1970.
    - Newspaper clippings, 1940-1970 (Box 122, Folder 1-10)
    - American Conservatory Theatre newspaper clippings - Undated (Box 122, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1972-1994 (Box 123, Folder 1-21)
  - Brochures and Press Releases, 1936-1994; 4.
    In this subseries are the marketing brochures and press releases of the Pittsburgh Playhouse. The materials are arranged chronologically by season.
    - Brochures and Press Releases, 1936-1973 (Box 124, Folder 1-22)
    - Brochures and Press Releases, 1973-1986 (Box 125A, Folder 1-14)
    - Brochures and Press Releases, 1986-1994 (Box 125B, Folder 1-8)
    - Brochures and Press Releases - Undated (Box 125B, Folder 9)
- Scripts/Production Books, VI.
  Playscripts of produced and considered works.
  - After the Fall, PPS 3591 (Box 126, Folder 1)
  - Animation: A Musical Comedy in 2 Acts, PPS 3592 (Box 126, Folder 2)
  - Anything Goes, PPS 3593 (Box 126, Folder 3)
  - Arms and the Man: A Pleasant Play, PPS 3594 (Box 126, Folder 4)
  - Blithe Spirit: An Impossible Farce in 3 Acts, PPS 3596 (Box 126, Folder 5)
  - Both Your Houses, PPS 3597 (Box 126, Folder 6)
  - Boys in the Band: A Play in 2 Acts, PPS 3598 (Box 127, Folder 1)
  - Cactus Flower: A Comedy in 2 Acts, PPS 3599 (Box 127, Folder 2)
  - Carousel, PPS 3600 (Box 127, Folder 3)
  - Carousel [Promptbook with Tech Plots], PPS 3600A (Box 127, Folder 4)
  - Cheating at Love, or the Magistrate, PPS 3601 (Box 127, Folder 5)
  - Cinderella, PPS (Box 127, Folder 6)
  - Complaisant Lover, PPS 3602 (Box 127, Folder 7)
  - Coronado's Children: A Comedy Satire in 3 Acts, PPS 3603 (Box 127, Folder 8)
  - Curious Savage: A Comedy in 3 Acts, PPS 3604 (Box 127, Folder 9)
  - Dear Me, The Sky Is Falling, PPS 3405 (Box 127, Folder 10)
  - Enter A Free Man, PPS (Box 128, Folder 1)
  - Fiddler on the Roof, PPS (Box 128, Folder 2)
  - The Entertainment, PPS 3606 (Box 128, Folder 3)
  - Flibberty Gibbet, His Last Chance, PPS 3607 (Box 128, Folder 4)
  - Fortnight, PPS 3608 (Box 128, Folder 5)
  - Forty Carats, PPS (Box 128, Folder 6)
  - Galileo, PPS 3609 (Box 128, Folder 7)
  - Ghetto: A Play in 3 Acts, PPS 3610 (Box 129, Folder 1)
  - Golden Crucible [2nd Draft], PPS 3611 (Box 129, Folder 2)
  - Golden Crucible [4th Draft/Final], PPS 3612 (Box 129, Folder 3)
  - Good Morning: A Comedy, PPS 3613 (Box 129, Folder 4)
  - Gypsy, PPS 3615 (Box 129, Folder 5-6)
  - Hansel and Gretel, PPS 3616 (Box 129, Folder 7)
  - Hay Fever: A Play in 3 Acts, PPS 3617 (Box 129, Folder 8)
  - Henry IV Part 1, PPS 3618 (Box 129, Folder 9)
  - In Case of Rain, PPS 3619 (Box 130, Folder 1)
  - King and I [Score only], PPS 3620 (Box 130, Folder 2)
  - King Midas and the Golden Touch, PPS (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - The Knack: A Comedy, PPS 3621 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Lady at Lely Square [Includes correspondence with the author], PPS 3622 (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - Last Full Measure, PPS 3623 (Box 130, Folder 6)
  - Last of the Red Hot Lovers, PPS (Box 130, Folder 7)
  - Legend of Harlequin, PPS 3624 (Box 130, Folder 8)
  - Lion in Winter: Comedy in 2 Acts, PPS 3625 (Box 130, Folder 9)
  - Little Foxes, PPS 3626 (Box 130, Folder 10)
  - Little Orphan, PPS 3627 (Box 130, Folder 11)
  - Little Wife, PPS 3628 (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - Loot, PPS 3629 (Box 131, Folder 2)
  - Lost in the Stars: Book and Lyrics, PPS 3630 (Box 131, Folder 3)
  - Luv, PPS 5091-5091A (Box 131, Folder 4-5)
  - Macbeth, PPS 3631 (Box 131, Folder 6)
  - Make a Million, PPS 3632 (Box 131, Folder 7)
  - Make a Note of It, PPS 3633 (Box 131, Folder 8)
  - Man From Home, PPS 3634 (Box 131, Folder 9)
  - Man of La Mancha, PPS 3635 (Box 131, Folder 10)
  - Marco and the Thieves, PPS 3636 (Box 132, Folder 1)
  - Marriage-Go-Round, PPS 3637 (Box 132, Folder 2)
  - Mary Stuart, PPS 3638 (Box 132, Folder 3)
  - The Mask and the Face: A Satire in 3 Acts, PPS 3639 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - The Matchmaker, PPS 3640 (Box 132, Folder 5)
  - Middle of the Night, PPS 3641 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - Midsummer Night's Dream, PPS 3642 (Box 132, Folder 7)
  - Mighty Mikko and the Fox, PPS 3643 (Box 132, Folder 8)
  - The Miles of Heaven: A Play in 5 Scenes, PPS 3644 (Box 132, Folder 9)
  - Mr. Ambassador, PPS 3645 (Box 132, Folder 10)
  - Mister Roberts, PPS 3646 (Box 132, Folder 11)
  - Moor Born, PPS 3647 (Box 133, Folder 1)
  - Morning's At Seven, PPS 3648 (Box 133, Folder 2)
  - Mousetrap: A Play in 2 Acts, PPS 3649 (Box 133, Folder 3)
  - My Friend the Fox, PPS 3650 (Box 133, Folder 4)
  - Mystery at Crooked Pine Ranch, PPS 5092 (Box 133, Folder 5)
  - Naughty Nifties, PPS 3651 (Box 133, Folder 6)
  - Never Too Late: A Comedy in 3 Acts, PPS 3652 (Box 133, Folder 7)
  - Nine Pine Street, PPS 3653 (Box 133, Folder 8)
  - No Strings, PPS 5093 (Box 133, Folder 9)
  - Odd Couple, PPS 3654 (Box 133, Folder 10)
  - Once Upon a Mattress, PPS 3655 (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - Owl and the Pussycat: A Comedy in 3 Acts, PPS 3656 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - Panda and the Spy, PPS 3657 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - The Patriarch: A Play in 3 Acts, PPS 3658 (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - Pied Piper, PPS 5094 (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - Play It Again, Sam: A Romantic Comedy in 3 Acts, PPS 3659 (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - Plaza Suite, PPS 3660 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie, PPS 5097 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - Remains To Be Seen, PPS 3662 (Box 135, Folder 1)
  - Rhinoceros, PPS 3663 (Box 135, Folder 2)
  - Rich Man, Poor Man: A Folk Play in 3 Acts, PPS 3664 (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Shoemaker and the Elves, PPS 3665 (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Still Life, PPS 3666 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - Streetcar Named Desire, PPS 5095 (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - Tavern: A Play in 3 Acts, PPS 3667 (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - Three Sisters, PPS 3668 (Box 135, Folder 8)
  - Three To Make Ready: A Comedy in 3 Acts, PPS 3669 (Box 135, Folder 9)
  - Three To One: Sketches and Lyrics, PPS 3670 (Box 136, Folder 1)
  - Tongue in Cheek: A Musical Revue, PPS 5096 (Box 136, Folder 2)
  - Two Hundred: Divided by Ten: An Original Play for Television, PPS 3671 (Box 136, Folder 3)
  - Uniting a Nation: A Historical Pageant, PPS 3672 (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - We Arrive As Strangers: A Play in 2 Acts, PPS 3673 (Box 136, Folder 5)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?, PPS 3674 (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf? [Promptbook with Tech Plots], PPS 3674 A (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - Woman in White Based on Collins Novel, PPS 3675 (Box 137, Folder 1)
  - You Can't Take It With You, PPS 3676 (Box 137, Folder 2)
  - You Can't Take It With You [Promptbook with Tech Plots], PPS 3676A (Box 137, Folder 3)
- Addendum 1, 1952-1969; VII.
  This addition of Pittsburgh Playhouse materials (mostly photographs) was added to the collection in May 1998.
  - Best Foot Forward, 1953 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Dance for Joy, 1952 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - Hackney, Doris (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Henry IV - Negatives (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Kiss for Cinderella, 1953-1954 (Box 138, Folder 5)
  - Macbeth, 1962 (Box 138, Folder 6)
  - Midas - Negatives (Box 138, Folder 7)
  - Nutcracker Ballet, 1968-1969 (Box 138, Folder 8)
  - Rumpelstiltskin, 1953 (Box 138, Folder 9)
  - Snow Queen, 1957 (Box 138, Folder 10)
  - Three to One, 1953 (Box 138, Folder 11)
  - Water Witch, 1951 (Box 138, Folder 12)
  - Ushers - Negatives (Box 138, Folder 13)
  - Unidentified photographs (Box 138, Folder 14-15)
- Addendum 2, 1962-1974; VIII.
  This addition of Pittsburgh Playhouse materials was added to the collection in July of 2011. The files are arranged alphabetically by folder title. Most of the materials are office files from the final few years of the Playhouse before complete control was transferred to Point Park College. Some folders have James Yeiser's name in the title. He was one of the managers of the Playhouse during this time period.
  - 1972-1973 Season - Proposed dates and budget (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - 1972-1973 Season - Subscriptions (Box 139, Folder 2)
  - 1973-1974 Season - Subscription sales campaign (Box 139, Folder 3)
  - 1974 Season - Marketing materials and correspondence with Hume Cronyn, 1973 (Box 139, Folder 4)
  - Accident reports, June 1972 (Box 139, Folder 5)
  - Account ledgers, 1970-1973 (Box 139, Folder 6)
  - Account journal entries, 1973 (Box 139, Folder 7)
  - Accounts payable - Restaurant, 1970 (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - Accounts payable - Theatre, 1970-1971 (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - Accounts receivable, July 1973 (Box 139, Folder 10)
  - Actor's Equity Association, 1968-1973 (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Advertising income, 1971 (Box 140, Folder 2)
  - Alfred the Great, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 3)
  - American Theatre Association - Production lists project, June 1, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 4)
  - Amusement Tax information, 1970-1973 (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - Applications for employment - blank (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Attendance graphs 1951-1971 (Box 140, Folder 7)
  - Bank reconciliation - Operating and deferred income accounts, 1972-1973 (Box 140, Folder 8)
  - Board meeting materials, 1972-1973 (Box 140, Folder 9)
  - Board members - Information (Box 140, Folder 10)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - Carousel, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 11)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - Elves and the Shoemaker, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 12)
  - Box Office statements and house manager's reports - Goldilocks, December 1972 (Box 140, Folder 13)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - How the Other Half Loves, October 1972 (Box 140, Folder 14)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - the Prime of Miss Jean Brodie, April 1973 (Box 140, Folder 15)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - Rapunzel and the Witch, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 16)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - Virginia Woolf and Yellow Submarine, December 1972 (Box 140, Folder 17)
  - Box office statements and house manager's reports - You Can't Take it With You, 1973 (Box 140, Folder 18)
  - Budget, 1971-1972 (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Budget, 1972-1973 (Box 141, Folder 2-3)
  - Budget, 1972-1974 (Box 141, Folder 4)
  - Budget, 1973 (Box 141, Folder 5)
  - Building insurance, 1971-1973 (Box 141, Folder 6)
  - Chamber of Commerce, 1972-1973 (Box 141, Folder 7)
  - Chart of accounts, 1971-1972 (Box 141, Folder 8)
  - Chart of accounts, 1972-1973 (Box 141, Folder 9)
  - Check requests, 1972 (Box 141, Folder 10)
  - Cincinnati Playhouse, 1973 (Box 141, Folder 11)
  - City of Pittsburgh - Correspondence, 1962-1973 (Box 141, Folder 12)
  - City of Pittsburgh - Sign Inspection, 1973-1974 (Box 141, Folder 13)
  - City of Pittsburgh - Taxes, 1971-1973 (Box 141, Folder 14)
  - Community relations, 1973 (Box 141, Folder 15)
  - Complaints, June 12, 1973 (Box 141, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 141, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence - In, 1971-1973 (Box 141, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Out, 1972-1973 (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and memos - Bills, 1972-1973 (Box 142, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and memos - General, 1971-1973 (Box 142, Folder 3-4)
  - Costumes - Anything Goes, September 17, 1971 (Box 142, Folder 5)
  - Craft Theatre - Painting, March 19, 1973 (Box 142, Folder 6)
  - Craft Theatre renovation, 1971-1972 (Box 142, Folder 7)
  - Craft Theatre renovation - Chairs and plaques, 1971 (Box 142, Folder 8)
  - Craft Theatre renovation - Chairs and plaques, 1971-1973 (Box 143, Folder 1)
  - Daily deposit sheets, 1972 (Box 143, Folder 2)
  - Daily membership payments, 1972-1973 (Box 143, Folder 3-4)
  - Dance entertainment contracts, February 1971 (Box 143, Folder 5)
  - Duquesne Light Company - Correspondence, June 12, 1972 (Box 143, Folder 6)
  - Employer's report of industrial injury forms - blank (Box 143, Folder 7)
  - Film Festival - Financial materials, 1973 (Box 143, Folder 8)
  - Film rental receipts, 1971-1973 (Box 143, Folder 9)
  - Fund raising, September 1973 (Box 143, Folder 10)
  - Hotel and Restaurant Employees Alliance - Local #237, 1969-1973 (Box 143, Folder 11)
  - Innovative Systems Inc. - Correspondence, November 1973 (Box 143, Folder 12)
  - Insurance information, 1972-1973 (Box 143, Folder 13)
  - Internal Revenue Service, 1973 (Box 143, Folder 14)
  - Internal Revenue Service, FICA, and withholding tax information, 1971-1973 (Box 143, Folder 15)
  - Jendoco Construction Corporation, 1972-1973 (Box 143, Folder 16)
  - Loti G. Falk scholarship, 1970-1971 (Box 143, Folder 17)
  - Manager procedures (Box 144, Folder 1)
  - Membership and season subscription, 1973 (Box 144, Folder 2)
  - Mercantile license tax, 1971-1974 (Box 144, Folder 3)
  - National Food Management Service, 1969-1972 (Box 144, Folder 4)
  - Neighborhood Youth Corps, 1972-1973 (Box 144, Folder 5)
  - Notes to balance sheets, 1970-1971 (Box 144, Folder 6)
  - Office services billing, 1973 (Box 144, Folder 7)
  - Payables ledger (Box 144, Folder 8)
  - Payroll, 1973 (Box 144, Folder 9)
  - Payroll account, June 1973 (Box 144, Folder 10)
  - Payroll - Semi-monthly, 1973 (Box 144, Folder 11)
  - Payroll - Weekly, 1973 (Box 144, Folder 12)
  - Pennsylvania Council on the Arts, November 20, 1973 (Box 144, Folder 13)
  - Personnel, 1971-1973 (Box 144, Folder 14)
  - Petty Cash sheets, 1971-1973 (Box 144, Folder 15)
  - Pittsburgh Ballet Theatre - Invoices, 1971 (Box 144, Folder 16)
  - Pittsburgh Playbill advertising, 1971-1973 (Box 144, Folder 17)
  - Point Park College - Arrangement with Pittsburgh Playhouse, 1971-1973 (Box 144, Folder 18)
  - Port Authority (Box 144, Folder 19)
  - Porters, 1972-1973 (Box 144, Folder 20)
  - Potential groups for discounts (Box 144, Folder 21)
  - Press books - Invoices, 1972-1973 (Box 145, Folder 1)
  - Productions - Permissions, Royalties, and Advertising, 1969-1971 (Box 145, Folder 2)
  - Purchase orders, 1969-1972 (Box 145, Folder 3)
  - Purveyors list (Box 145, Folder 4)
  - Reports, 1966-1967 (Box 145, Folder 5)
  - Reports of the director, 1965-1966 (Box 145, Folder 6)
  - Rock concerts, 1973 (Box 145, Folder 7)
  - Royalty fees - Adaptation/Next, 1972 (Box 145, Folder 8)
  - Royalty fees - Boys in the Band, 1972 (Box 145, Folder 9)
  - Royalty fees - Brave Little Tailor, 1972 (Box 145, Folder 10)
  - Royalty fees - the Elves and the Shoemaker, 1973 (Box 145, Folder 11)
  - Royalty fees - Land of the Dragon, 1971 (Box 145, Folder 12)
  - Royalty fees - Never too Late, 1972 (Box 145, Folder 13)
  - Royalty fees - Play it Again, Sam, January 1972 (Box 145, Folder 14)
  - Royalty fees - Plaza Suite, January 1972 (Box 145, Folder 15)
  - Sales reports, 1972-1973 (Box 145, Folder 16)
  - Sales tax, 1971-1973 (Box 145, Folder 17)
  - Samuel French, 1972-1973 (Box 145, Folder 18)
  - Schedule of operating income and expenses (Box 145, Folder 19)
  - Schneider Technology Services, 1971-1972 (Box 145, Folder 20)
  - Sound system - RCA service report, 1972 (Box 145, Folder 21)
  - Special mailings, 1973 (Box 145, Folder 22)
  - Staff and faculty list (Box 145, Folder 23)
  - Staff policies and procedures, September 1972 (Box 145, Folder 24)
  - Stage Door Club - Deposits and ledgers, 1972-1973 (Box 145, Folder 25)
  - Stage Door Club - Membership cards (Box 145, Folder 26)
  - Stage Door Club - Monthly membership report, February 1971 (Box 145, Folder 27)
  - Stage manager's report - Androcles and the Lion, November 4, 1973 (Box 145, Folder 28)
  - State tax, 1970-1974 (Box 146, Folder 1)
  - Subscription ledgers (Box 146, Folder 2-3)
  - Tax exempt forms, 1970-1972 (Box 147, Folder 1)
  - Telephone campaign sales, 1972-1973 (Box 147, Folder 2)
  - Theatre rentals, 1971-1972 (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Theatre Techniques Incorporated - Lightboard, 1971-1973 (Box 147, Folder 4)
  - Ticket prices (Box 147, Folder 5)
  - Ticket Reservation Systems Inc., 1970 (Box 147, Folder 6)
  - Ticketron, 1973-1974 (Box 147, Folder 7)
  - Vendors binder, 1971-1973 (Box 147, Folder 8)
  - Wage tax, 1971 (Box 147, Folder 9)
  - Warner Bros. Distributing Corporation - Exhibitor's report (Box 147, Folder 10)
  - Weekly income, 1972-1973 (Box 147, Folder 11)
  - Weekly sales report, 1972-1973 (Box 147, Folder 12-13)
  - Yeisner correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 147, Folder 14)